# **Alaina Kafkes**

#### **Awards**

#### **Anita Borg Institute Scholar**

June 2016. Won an all-expenses paid trip to the Grace Hopper Celebration for excellence in innovation & leadership.

#### PanHellenic Scholar

May 2016. Received a merit scholarship that honors exceptional undergraduates of Greek-American heritage.

# Personal Projects

#### Hacktoberfest

October 2016.

Contributed bug fixes & new features to four open source codebases. Implemented parenthesis & quotation matching for Nteract. Languages used: JavaScript.

## Myrror

January 2016 - April 2016.

Developed and cast a web app onto a twoway mirror in order to assess young adult body confidence using the principles of social comparison theory. Pitched proof of concept to 50+ students and professors. Technologies used: JavaScript, JQuery, Firebase API.

#### Dibz

January 2016 - June 2016.

Founded and developed a web app that offers online sellers the ability to generate a bitlink to share a listing in informal, online communities. Launched to 50+ beta testers. Technologies used: JavaScript, RiotJS, Firebase API, HTML/CSS.

#### Rude

February 2016 (HackIllinois).

Coded Android app that encourages users to spend quality time socializing without checking their phone. Technologies used: Java, Facebook API.

#### Education

#### Northwestern University | Computer Science, Chemistry

Bachelor's Degree Anticipated June 2017. Cumulative GPA: 3.69/4.00 Coursework: Artificial Intelligence; Operating Systems; Human-Computer Interaction; Machine Learning; Robotics; Data Structures & Algorithms.

# Work Experience

#### Delta Lab | iOS Engineer & UX Researcher

September 2016 – Present. Building an iOS app that helps users build habits in running & mindfulness while simultaneously crowdsourcing data about their surroundings for citizen science projects. Languages used: Swift.

## Clarifai | Remote Developer Evangelist (Champion)

August 2016 – November 2016. Presented tutorials on APIs and Git to audiences of 500+ listeners. Created data visualizations that showcase the gender gap in engineering & medicine using the Clarifai API. Wrote a viral blog post encouraging new coders to contribute to open source. Named one of the top three (out of forty-some) champions. Technologies used: Python, d3.js, Twitter API, Bing API.

## **GE Healthcare | Software Engineering Intern**

June 2016 – August 2016. Contributed 300+ lines of code to the Media Manager web app, which expedites the binding of images & videos to patient data in a vendor-neutral archive. Spearheaded the creation of a mock server to prevent end-to-end testing with sensitive patient information. Technologies used: AngularJS 2, NodeJS, ExpressJS, TypeScript, HTML/CSS.

# Northwestern University | Teaching Assistant

*December 2015 – December 2016.* Assists students in two computer science courses with object-oriented programming, discrete math, and graph theory questions. Languages used: C++.

#### Extracurriculars & Offices Held

### BuildHer | Founder & Head of Hacker Experience

*July 2016 – Present.* Launching the first-ever student-run women's hackathon in Chicago to foster beginner participation and interdisciplinary pursuits.

# Women in Computing | Internal President

April 2015 – Present. Established mentorship program for undergraduate & graduate women in tech, with 40+ participants in the pilot program. Organizes and teaches at weekly campus hack nights with 100+ attendees.